<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://malachimabie.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://malachimabie.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-05T18:15:24-10:00</updated><id>http://malachimabie.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Malachi Mabie</title><subtitle>Portfolio website where case studies of past projects will reside, as well as anchoring live projects. I&apos;m coding this so that I can add markdown files and not deal with weird website builders. I&apos;m using Jekyll, which uses Ruby. This paragraph is located in _config.yml and is appearing in feed.xml.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How my career is changing</title><link href="http://malachimabie.com/bio,/cover/2021/04/04/cover-letter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How my career is changing" /><published>2021-04-04T11:28:27-10:00</published><updated>2021-04-04T11:28:27-10:00</updated><id>http://malachimabie.com/bio,/cover/2021/04/04/cover-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://malachimabie.com/bio,/cover/2021/04/04/cover-letter.html">&lt;p&gt;I have five years of engineering work experience, divided between software, machine learning, and mechanical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotic design brought me to automation, for manufacturing minimally invasive surgery devices. Then I transferred to UCSD for Machine Learning and Neural Computation, where I’ve explored so many of my interests with terrific resources and faculty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like software engineering enables the same abstract creative thinking I treasured in mechanical design, while providing a limitless toolkit for developing intuition and scaling effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Endura Technologies our product involved an audio application for deep learning. The algorithm was ultimately visual based, and a pipeline filtered and re-represented audio training snippets for it. At UCSD, I took Neural Signal Processing, which improved my toolkit and understanding in this area. After that, I supported an applications engineer with testing and process automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;short-list-of-highlights&quot;&gt;Short list of highlights:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Coded readable, interfaced, faster runtime testing routines that used to take weekends to run and half a week’s worth of hours to be manually altered per test.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Automated several steps of long and error prone coding by generating java code from an excel spreadsheet of register functions using python.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Designed, manufactured, and qualified more than fifty End-of-Arm tooling for the polymer injection moulding process using stock and custom machined grippers and linkages, being assigned the most challenging molds that needed creative solutions for retrieval and sensing. Each tool saves thousands of dollars per run from mold damage and variance, as well as hundreds of man hours otherwise spent separating part and sprue.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Collaborated with executives and the automation department on larger projects, aiding in design choices and product development as well as user experience, troubleshooting and qualification.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A heavy tool kept misaligning with the mold, damaging ejection pins and not retrieving parts consistently. Designed and constructed double spring loaded alignment pin retrofits that not only saved lots of money, but had the most satisfying tactile feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;story-about-my-last-project-at-applied-medical&quot;&gt;Story about my last project at Applied Medical:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;A cutting edge metal injection insert moulding process for a new suturing device was costing $100,000/month in variance from pin misalignment, as well as being a super slow and awkward task for production.
My guess was that the magnetic pen being used was causing some pins to polarize and repel from their channel. After ordering some fishing line variants and a suction pen intended for microchips, I 3D printed a perfectly sized grid with rods and imprints for the fishing line to fold into, and designed stainless steel suction pen tips. Pouring in the two-pronged pins, they would face the same direction hanging between the lines, with the aberrant ones falling through the grate and pooling to the corner for recycling. The best of my pen tips then created a vortex around the cap of the pins so that they stayed set at a predictable angle rather than collapsing to a different orientation or changing angle when pressed against the insert mold. It also had a notch to tune the operator in with the insert mold channel.
When implemented into production, it completely solved the variance issue, and sped up the shop orders significantly. I had a working prototype ready soon after the ordered components arrived, thanks to effective prototyping and vertical integration.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bio," /><category term="cover" /><summary type="html">I have five years of engineering work experience, divided between software, machine learning, and mechanical.</summary></entry></feed>